<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KoStard&#39;s Home Page</title>
    <link>https://kostard.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on KoStard&#39;s Home Page</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 15:23:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kostard.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Meaninglessness</title>
      <link>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/meaninglessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 22:21:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/meaninglessness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I had ideas about the world or a thing I wanted to do, I would quickly disregard them saying that it&amp;rsquo;s not objectively valuable, so I need something better, stronger, more meaningful, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then after a few years of continuous spiraling, I asked this &lt;a href=&#34;../the-simple-questions&#34;&gt;simple question&lt;/a&gt;:&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Is there anything objectively valuable?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This led me through a chain of thoughts coming after each other, that eventually resulted in this experiment:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are the only living organism in the universe. Just a single human, on this huge planet, that at the same time is tiny in the context of galaxies, universe, etc. And the point is, try to accept that this is the reality, not like this is some kind of a trick and someone else is hiding behind the next rock with a camera. No, you are the only living organism. Now&amp;hellip; Is there anything you want to do? You might get hungry, want to drink water, etc. But is there anything that you can do that is meaningful for you? Do you want to do math? Physics research? Chemistry? You might want to satisfy some personal needs or interests, but what&amp;rsquo;s the point of it?&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Simple Questions</title>
      <link>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/the-simple-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 22:01:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/the-simple-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Throughout my life, I always liked discussing about the world, different philosophies and ideas, exploring and investigating new concepts, etc. And inevitably, I had several discussions when one of us felt misunderstood and we couldn&amp;rsquo;t come to a common ground. It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to fall into the spiral of continuous word picking, going into the details without agreeing on the fundaments and after hours getting out of it feeling like it was completely meaningless, possibly feeling hurt, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Why in Life</title>
      <link>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/the-why-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 21:58:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kostard.github.io/blog/2023/06/the-why-in-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe everything we do in life should serve a tree of &lt;a href=&#34;../the-simple-questions&#34;&gt;simple questions&lt;/a&gt;, asking the &amp;ldquo;why&amp;quot;s of everything. Why do you want to do the thing you want? Why do you want to have a job? Rather than the easier answers like &amp;ldquo;Well I need money&amp;rdquo;, go deeper and build this tree defining who you really are. Why do you need money? What is your dream, why do you want that?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://kostard.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 16:01:39 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kostard.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there 👋&#xA;My name is Ruben, and I&amp;rsquo;m a curious person who loves using philosophical ideas and answers to solve real-world problems. My moments of wonder have led me to study and use programming for these purposes (more than 5 years of professional experience).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Software Development Engineer at Amazon, I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about solving problems that matter and always looking for new challenges. I work on making cross-border expansion easier for our sellers and bringing more products to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools I&#39;ve made</title>
      <link>https://kostard.github.io/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 15:50:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kostard.github.io/tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;here-you-can-find-some-of-my-tools&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Here you can find some of my tools:&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#here-you-can-find-some-of-my-tools&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kostard.github.io/petrol_price_history_arm/&#34;&gt;Prices tracker for petrol and diesel in Armenia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kostard.github.io/ansi2unicode-web/&#34;&gt;Armenian ANSI to Unicode translator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kostard.github.io/web_ocr/&#34;&gt;OCR tool running inside your browser (supports Armenian)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KoStard/itunes-search-cli&#34;&gt;iTunes CLI Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
